How are you?
I'm well - thank you, Sir.
Where you were living before, you are no longer there.
It's true.
Where you were before, you are no longer there.
You just left. Transition.
You want to leave your husband; you are already in the process of divorce.
Yes, man of God.
What happened?
I'm in the process of divorcing, man of God.
I just left my home.
Clap for Jesus Christ.
I want to see you.
You have to receive counselling before you take this step.
In your home, divorce, divorce and divorce.
That's true, man of God.
You are the only person who has a stable home.
That’s very true, sir.
And two; internet – I want to advise you over it.
Yes, man of God.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Linda Ejiogu.
I am a South African married to a Nigerian.
The prophecy the man of God gave me last week Sunday was on point.
The first thing he said to me was that I had moved houses.
What was happening was that there was a spirit of divorce
that is in my family and there was transition in my life.
He mentioned something about the internet.
The prophecy the man of God said is very true because on 9th February 2014, I moved out of my marital house.
I had been living there with my husband for 17 years.
I left the house because he had been very abusive to me all these years.
He would threaten to kill me, to pour acid on me.
He would hit me in front of my kids.
He had done many things to me; he would stab me.
I don’t even buy knives in my house because I am scared of him.
He always threatened me; he has a very big problem with anger.
And other things; they were not major things to me to leave the marriage, but cheating...
He has cheated on me; he is a serial cheater.
He has numerous girlfriends in South Africa and in Nigeria.
There is nothing he doesn’t do.
Married women, single, young, old, he is following them.
Since 2004, he took away my daughter.
I brought the child here to Nigeria; I came with her.
That girl, I left her in 2006.
We are talking of reconciliation.
I will not want you to go too far.
I think my brother is around.
Yes, man of God.
Let me see my brother; I don't want you to go too far.
We are talking of reconciliation.
You have said your own story.
If my brother is around too, he has his own side of story.
My brother - thank you for honouring me and coming here today - thank you very much.
Thank you man of God - it is a pleasure to see you.
Let him stand here.
Do you have any other thing you want to say?
I do, man of God.
What I want to say is that I have a daughter here since eight years now.
And this child...
It was an argument between him and I
that she would come here to attend school and learn the culture.
Since then, I have not seen my child.
It is all right.
Let me hear from my brother here.
Don't cry, don't begin to get sympathy to your side.
It is God Almighty that brings this matter.
You came to the Synagogue on your own and you were here for a different thing.
You carried placard; what was written on the placard was different from what I was telling you.
You never put it on the paper that this was your problem but you had a different problem.
When I got to you, I was telling you what was not revealed on the paper.
So, it was God who was talking.
OK?
If God can bring such a secret story out, the same God should tell you people the outcome.
OK, brother - I want to thank you for...
After the prophecy was given and I asked her where was her husband,
she said he was in South Africa, isn't it?
Yes, man of God.
I said, "I want to see your husband".
Thank God, you say he is a Nigerian - he can not hear my voice and say he would not come.
Immediately we made a call to the man and he came, just because of the prophecy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Just because of the prophecy... and you know the marriage is broken already.
There is nothing like marriage any more but just because he heard me talking.
He could have said, "No, I don't need to go there, the woman is no longer my wife, what am I going to do?"
But he said, "I have to be there because man of God is calling me".
So, thank you for that.
Let's hear from you.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Chief Maxwell Ejiogu
I am from Imo State, Nigeria.
I reside in South Africa.
I have been in South Africa for 17 years.
The lady beside me here is my wife.
First of all, before I go into detail, I would like to thank God who made it possible
for me to be here today through the prophecy given to my family
through our humble man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua.
I thank you so much.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
OK, you say our sister beside you is your wife or ex-wife - what are you saying?
She is still my wife for now.
Thank you very much.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Because he has the fear of God, and for him to say that...
OK, let's hear.
Without wasting much of our time, I would like to go into detail.
The prophecy the man of God gave us is true.
I have the documents here.
It is a confirmed prophecy.
I have heard what my wife said.
The issue is that I love my wife.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My sister - thank you.
As I was saying, since I met my wife in 1997, the first problem we had was alcohol.
There is a hotel that is called Mimosa.
She asked me to take her there.
I took her there.
When she was drinking, I told her that I wanted to go and sleep.
Let us go.
She attacked me with a bottle of beer.
I am a kind of person who is shy; I just pretended and went upstairs.
She followed me.
She took a bottle and attacked me, took a chair and hit me on my head.
OK, when she was under the influence of alcohol... ?
Alcohol.
Thank you.
It was not her; it was when she was under the influence of alcohol.
There were two people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There were two people talking.
When she was under the influence of alcohol she attacked,
but when she is not under the influence of alcohol - she is a good woman.
OK, thank you - go ahead.
Since that day, fighting over alcohol and smoking never stopped in my family.
I had endured it for 17 years but this thing did not stop.
She mingles with people who are divorced.
If I told her something, she wouldn’t listen to me.
When she is under the influence of alcohol.
Thank you.
She goes out in the morning...
OK.
You know this is not the way you married her.
You never saw her under the influence of alcohol when you married her.
Yes, I never saw her.
OK, thank you.
You too you have some blame.
You married somebody who you never saw under the influence of alcohol.
Suddenly, when she started living with you, she started taking alcohol.
Where were you when she started it?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
OK, you can leave the issue of alcohol.
We know what anyone can do under the influence of alcohol.
They can even do worse than things you are talking about.
Forget about being under the influence of alcohol.
Tell us the other side of the story, sir.
Thank you for your coming once again.
Man of God, sometimes, she would go out in the morning
and come back the following day, 1 or 2 am.
She would be drunk and driving my kids.
When I talked, the next thing she would so is call the police.
She would tell me that the women of South Africa have got the right, 50:50.
That would hurt me.
I would tell her, "Listen, before I married you, I told you that I have culture.
You knew that I am a traditionalist and a titled man, respect me.
I don’t like a situation where I give you a law or tell you, "don’t do this
and you do it a hundred times, that makes me angry and I have a hot temper."
When I start enduring this, enduring that, there will be an extent where I will not be able to take it any more.
Fighting will burst out.
She had been taking me to court and putting me in jail.
Sometimes, I would be in for one week, three days without eating inside the cell.
She would be able to do whatever she wanted to do inside the house.
Afterwards, my brother would have to beg her so that she would release me.
In the police station?
In the police station.
OK, you went to station - you were in the prison for how many days?
Sometimes she could put me in police custody for three days, sometimes one week.
And what makes me angry so much - I love my kids, I don't play with my kids.
OK, thank you uncle.
My daughter, thank you.
There is something you said that covers it all.
You said, "She is my wife".
She is my wife.
And you love her so much.
I love her so much.
Thank you very much.
The person you love so much and the person that is your wife
is the person that is not under the influence of alcohol.
Here is T.B. Joshua.
She needs deliverance, you need deliverance.
After the deliverance we will have our real persons, our real value.
Your real value - you will discover it.
Her real value - she will discover it.
Now, the love you are talking about is still there.
Thank you.
So now, all the story - we realize that our sister here was under the influence of alcohol,
that is why all those things were happening.
She is not her.
It is that spirit - so, therefore it is not her.
Like I have said - when you met her and married her, you never saw her as a drunkard.
It was when she got to your house, in one way or the other she saw you taking alcohol but not so much of it.
But a little boy - when you show him how to jump, he will want to jump more and more.
That it is.
So, I want to tell you, "thank you very much for the love have for me".
I want to come to this marriage.
God is here.
I want to tell you, this marriage is from God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is from God.
After the deliverance I will pray with you people.
I want to meet you people for a discussion, to let you know that...
Please, let us put our past behind us and more forward.
It is not by accident you met him; it is not by accident you met her.
This is a marriage.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whatever she must have done to you in the past, please put it behind you.
OK?
The Lord that said, "thou shall not drink alcohol", also said, "thou shall not smoke, thou shall not fornicate".
If you have drunk alcohol - you have fornicated...
So please, let's put everything behind and move forward.
God is still saying something.
We shouldn’t look at the wrong; let us look at what God says about the wrong.
Tell your neighbour: "Don't look at the wrong; listen to what God says about that wrong".
God sometimes uses the wrong to speak to us, to teach us a lesson
and to prepare us or to strengthen the marriage.
God will sometimes allow this wrong to happen in order to strengthen the marriage.
It is mostly misunderstanding that is standing the marriage.
When you see any wonderful marriage today -
if you know how many misunderstandings they have gone through, before they established
that solid and wonderful marriage.
They have gone through the valley of shadow of death.
There is no marriage that grew strong by understanding.
Misunderstanding will come many times before understanding.
There can be no understanding without misunderstanding.
There can be no understanding without what?
[Misunderstanding.]
There can be no right without wrong.
Tell your neighbour.
"There can be no right without wrong."
There can be no right without wrong.
[There can be no right without wrong.]
There can be no understanding without misunderstanding.
[There can be no understanding without misunderstanding.]
Please, I want to meet you people.
If I allow you to talk, sir - I think we will just continue to repeat ourselves.
I know you want to answer her; she says you had many concubines...
You want to answer her by saying she has many boyfriends...
If I'm right...
You are right, Man of God.
What are we going to say about that?
You have many concubines - you too, you have many boyfriends.
You have many black - you too have many black.
You have many hurts - you too have many hurts.
So, we know, you continue to repeat yourself - because you have stated those points
you want to answer her.
Please, let's put everything behind us.
Thank you, my sister.
Thank you for coming.
I want to thank you for just accepting my call.
I will want to join this marriage.
You people are to wait for me.
You go to the prayer line.
I know the worst has happened.
The same worst will now bring the best.
[Amen.]
Yes. Therefore - let everybody go and seat separately for now.
Because they have been sitting separately, they never came together.
So, they have to do the same thing until prayer line.
After prayer line I will be the one to bring them together.
OK, uncle - you can go back to your seat here.
[Thank you man of God.]
You go back to your seat.
It's too soon to begin to say, "hug yourself".
No - that is not an issue of a hug.
There are issues on the ground already.
So, we have to disclose before we hug.
Man of God, please I want you to collect this divorce summons from me from the High Court.
My sister, come out.
Can you see what I'm talking about?
There is a court issue already.
There is a divorce order against me.
By my sister?
She filed it.
This one is for the children’s court.
It is still going on.
This one is for the divorce.
There is another one…
No - it's all right.
You know I said, that I could not ask you to hug here .
For you to know that I know what is on the ground...
After the deliverance I still need to sit with them.
We are in the midway.
OK, here is my sister, you are my brother.
Give me, I will give it to my sister.
My sister will get it.
Help me to hold it.
Thank you.
Help me to hold it, my sister.
You keep it for me.
Go and sit down.
My sister, come here.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know what happened?
My sister collected it and...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
She will give me it.
After the prayer I will collect it back.
We will discuss, I will answer: "what happened?" - "you have gone too far".
Divorce already - you have sent the divorce documents.
You will be the one to go ahead and do the rest.
You will go and withdraw it by yourself.
Can you see?
I said I could not ask them to hug themselves because I know there are many issues to be settled.
Suddenly they come here saying there is a divorce letter.
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Linda Ejiogu.
The gentleman standing next to me is my husband Maxwell Ejiogu.
Beside him is our first daughter, after her our son and his auntie - my husband's older sister.
that takes care of them.
You are very welcome once again.
Can you just recount to us the first day you came here - you received that prophecy.
Tell us once again what the man of God said to you and how that word of prophecy was true for your life.
As I was standing in the prayer line I had that expectation within me
because I knew exactly what I came here for.
On the placard I have put what was written on the medical report.
But you cannot hide from God.
God knew how I was feeling at that time.
He had to come to us through the man of God - Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The man of God told me exactly what was happening in our lives.
That day - it was about three weeks after my moving out.
I filed for divorce.
Prophet said that the spirit of divorce was in my family - which was very true.
I was the one who was still married - it's very true.
Prophet spoke to me and told me everything that I knew.
I was not in shock though because I knew he was a real man of God.
I prayed to God that He would speak if this marriage was really from Him.
God will come through for us - for me to be able to save the marriage.
After the prophecy, by the grace of God, your husband was invited to The SCOAN.
He flew all the way from South Africa.
Tell us what happened last week during the service, when the man of God -
Prophet T.B. Joshua addressed this issue.
During the service when I had to testify, the man of God called my husband who then confessed his love for me.
That was something that I knew, and he knew that I loved him too.
My husband mentioned his own grievances to the man of God.
From then...
The thing that caused all this he was talking about - my drinking, going out, I drove with my kids while being drunk and all that -
it was because of loneliness.
I felt rejected and I would just leave the house and go out.
When I saw him here last Friday, we were not even talking, we stared at each other.
After the deliverance something strange happened.
The anger I had...
The way I felt has just changed.
I felt peace within me.
I had that urge - this marriage can still work, we can still do things right.
I thank God for The SCOAN and Emmanuel TV, because without it we wouldn't know that there is a living God.
Our kids would have been raised like us - which I fought against my whole life.
I wanted my kids to be raised by me and my husband as a family.
Well, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Madam, during the course of the service last week, after yourself and your husband had explained the challenges
you were facing, the man of God made a statement that it was deliverance that you and your husband needed,
and that this was indeed a marriage from Heaven.
Now, can you just testify - ever since your received prayer from the man of God at the prayer line,
and God revealed that in the service - what were the changes that you've seen in your relationship
with your husband in this week, and what do you want to testify about that?
From Monday we started to have conversation, and it was more calm, in the sense that he could listen,
I could finish my sentence without him biting my head off.
We started talking, communicating very well.
There is an open communication now, whereby I can explain something to him and he would listen attentively
and acknowledged that he had heard what I had been saying.
God has delivered us and it is permanent, in the mighty name of Jesus.
Thank You, Jesus Christ.
Tell us; ever since the deliverance - do you still have that urge to smoke or drink or go outside?
Well, since the deliverance I don't have that urge for anything.
I'm calm, I'm at peace with myself.
Those things happened when I was angry - I just snaped out - I was like, "Well, let me just go out there".
But now I'm very much at peace.
I really thank God for delivering us.
How have you been sleeping ever since that deliverance?
I sleep really peacefully.
I find it easy to sleep.
I don't turn and start thinking way forward or way back.
I just believe that all is well with me and my family.
Thank You, Jesus.
Finally, last week, publicly the divorce letter was brought out and the man of God actually handed it over to you.
Tell us what is your decision concerning that particular letter.
Well, the divorce papers are with me right now.
When I go back to South Africa...
They were issued from the High Court in Pretoria.
When I go back now, I will speak to my lawyer and I will withdraw the divorce because...
I know that our marriage has been healed.
We are looking forward to greater things, peace and harmony.
Thank you.
Well, let's put our hands together for our Lord; Jesus Christ!
We thank God Almighty; how God has really intervened in this marriage and thank God, through this word
of prophecy and the deliverance, the couple is no longer gonna go through divorce, but is going to continue
to live together in Christ Jesus.
Indeed, this is the power of prophecy.
We give all the glory to our Lord; Jesus Christ.
Finally madam, I believe with the experience you have passed through in this marriage,
you have a lot of advises and lessons for people to learn from.
What is your advise to people watching you right now, especially to married couples?
What I would advise is: seek the face of God and the foundation of the marriage is very important.
We got married when we were very young.
There was no proper foundation, there was no God there.
I think that people need counselling before they get married.
They need to know God, they need to know what they are putting that marriage into.
Right now, I believe that our marriage has a new foundation.
I thank God for the prophecy, for the generosity in this place, for the love that was given to us.
Thank you.
Right now, we would like to hear few words from your husband as well.
Sir, you are welcome.
If you could introduce yourself to us and tell us your own experiences and your own testimony.
My name is Maxwell Ejiogu.
First of all, I thank God Almighty, who made it possible for us to be here.
Last week, when we were here, I was standing here with my wife
but we were not able to look into each others eyes.
Today, we can look into each others eyes.
So...
I thank God for that and I thank our prophet T.B. Joshua, who described the problem in the family.
Because to me...
I have already decided to welcome this divorce.
She knows me.
It can take me a minute to decide what I want to do.
She knows what I am capable of.
But God saw it and picked it and dealt with it - glory be to God.
Tell us sir, ever since you spoke out last weekend's service...
The man of God, prophet T.B. Joshua said it was deliverance that was needed both on your side,
and on her side.
He prayed for both of you.
What are the changes in your relationship with your wife ever since then?
That last Sunday, when I came here, when I had a handshake with man of God I felt something.
Something happened in my life.
At the beginning I was very angry with my wife and I said that there was nobody who could change my mind.
I told her, she knows; as you already gave me those summons - I'm fine.
After my handshake with man of God I felt something.
My anger started to reduce.
I couldn't know what to say any more so I just kept quiet.
When he said that this marriage was from heaven - I was finished, I couldn't...
That day man of God conducted the deliverance for both of us.
To be honest - I'm very calm.
I'm no more stressed.
I don't think of worldly things.
I'm OK.
We can talk, we can interact, we can relate now.
We can share ideas.
I believe everything is normal in our relationship.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
What a wonderful testimony.
We give glory to God Almighty for restoring this marriage.
Indeed, only our Lord Jesus Christ could do this.
Right now sir, your wife has just said that she is going to withdraw that divorce letter.
How do you feel hearing that?
I felt good because the order is from above; she has to do it.
So, I'm happy that she is withdrawing the summon.
Hellelujah.
We thank Jesus Christ for indeed restoring this marriage.
We can actually see that you have your children here.
We just want to hear quick word from your daughter as well.
Sister, tell us your name and where you are from.
My name is Ejiogu.
What can you say about what Jesus Christ has done for your parents?
I am so happy for what Jesus Christ done for me because
when I heard that my father and mum wanted to divorce I felt so sad and I felt like crying.
But right now?
I feel happy.
Thank You, Jesus Christ.
Well, to the glory of God we want to encourage this family, now, when they made the Word of God
the standard for their lives - they must continue to stay close to Jesus.
We can see that our mother here is crying tears of joy knowing that God has finally reconciled this marriage.
We want to encourage you to continue to make the Word of God the standard for your lives as you do so
the best is yet to come, in Jesus' name.
[Amen.]
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God’s power at work in our generation today,
and stay up to date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons, and testimonies from SCOAN
Emmanuel TV; changing lives, changing nations, and changing the world.